Setumadhava Giridhar Kathawate

206-739-4983 setugk@uw.edu Seattle, WA www.setumadhava.com

About

UX designer having 2.8 years of experience seeking opportunities to solve complex user & business problems through elegant, research-informed product & experience designs.

Other interests include Machine Learning & Behavioral Psychology.

Skills

Interaction Design & Prototyping, Axure, Framer, Invision, Interface & Visual design, Wireframes, Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, Understanding of Research methodologies to analyze & measure user behavior, Contextual Inquiry, User Interviews, Personas, Designing usable patterns & products, HTML/CSS/SASS, Python, Arduino, Cross Functional Collaboration skills, Design strategy, Agile methodologies, Machine Learning basics, Android (Material) & iOS design languages.

Relevant Courses

User-Centered Design, Usability Studies, Data Science for UX Researchers, Visual Communication, Interaction Design & Prototyping, Machine Learning (Coursera).

Experience

PREMERA BLUE CROSS, UX DESIGNER

MAY 2017 - PRESENT

- Led the UX efforts to design Premera's healthcare search experience to help customers confidently find the right healthcare they're looking for.
- Average customer satisfaction score went up from 2.8 to 4.1 (on a scale of 1-5) after shipping the new search experience.

EVENTOSAUR, CO-FOUNDER & PRODUCT DESIGNER

MAR 2015 - JAN 2017

 Led the design & research efforts to design an e-commerce platform to simplify traditional event planning process by connecting hosts with event service vendors.

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON LIBRARIES, USABILITY RESEARCHER

SEP 2016 - MAR 2017

- Collaborated with UW Library's research team to run Usability Studies on the Library search website with 12 participants.
- The UW Library Search website was re-designed and shipped based on the recommendations from this study.

EXPEDIA INC, INTERACTION DESIGN INTERN

JUN 2016 - SEP 2016

Conceptualized & designed a mobile web interface to explore alternative hotel shopping experience for Expedia's customers by simplifying the beds & occupancy preferences, room browsing & checkout process.

Education

MASTER'S IN HUMAN CENTERED DESIGN & ENGINEERING

SEP 2015 - MAR 2017

University of Washington, Seattle; GPA 3.92/4.0

BACHELOR'S IN ELECTRONICS & COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING

AUG 2006 - JUN 2010

Visvesvaraya Technological University, Bangalore, India; GPA 6.9/10.0

Awards

BEST GRADUATE CAPSTONE PROJECT - PUMP IT UP

JUN 2017

University of Washington, Seattle

Designed an Android app and an IOT system prototypes that provide residents contextual information & better control over existing water systems to reduce water waste in India.